GP PLS Notes:

1) Talk to Tomas about his improved gradient variance measures. Would be useful in benchmarking (once the line search is working)
2) ProbWolfe from PLS is good, will have to use it. 
3) Cubic GP is key to make this work.
4) Expected improvement is a GP way to ask what is the expectation that a specific point is better than another point (I THINK)
5) Expected improvement can be used to determine a) failure of mcsearch candidate selection, or b) determining if one point is 'significantly' improved upon another.
6) Is expected improvement used to determine if a new candidate point is better than what has already been found? ->yes
7) PLS obeys strong Wolfe conditions.
8) Function and gradient variances are not computed for every point. Rather, only the function and gradient variance at the origin of the line search are used in GP throughout.
9) Rescaled space is used throughout the line search to improve stability and reduce the number of hyper-parameters. One of the consequences of this is that we should NOT be squeezing the variance, etc. It probably ruins some of the estimation going on in the line search.
10) Need to understand why 'Matrix is close to singular or badly scaled' errors take place when computing covariances of the GP in the 'UpdateGP()' function. This was occurring when the exact variance was being tested. As somewhat expected, the ExpectedImprovement calculation was causing errors in computation, especially due to some faulty error function usage. The updateGP() function creates new functions for the various variance, covariance, function, and gradient estimates when the A vector and G matrix are updated


Testing adaptive noise (where the sigmas of the gp are updated when a noisier point is encountered), Tomas' improved variance + adaptive noise, and Tomas's improved variance + exact noise (i.e. sigma is different at each point)

Gaussian (nEpochs to convergence), batchsize=10 [2000 samples each]
Adaptive noise: 141.68 epochs, 169.70 data loops, 1.95 function evals per line search call
Improved variance: 161.53 epochs, 191.47 data loops, 1.7073 function evals per line search call
Exact noise: 192.57 epochs, 227.48 data loops, 1.625 function evals per line search call
Non-adaptive noise: 121.37 epochs, 145.06 data loops, 1.90 function evals per line search call

Branin, avg.dist from true min after 1000 epochs, batchsize=200 [200 samples each] <some converge, highly path dependent>
Adaptive noise: 988.01 epochs, 1370.6 data loops, 1.87 function evals per line search call, .2545 distance
Improved variance: 979.74 epochs, 1369.4 data loops, 1.9766 function evals per line search call, .2217 distance
Exact noise: Note: Matrix is close to singular/badly scaled errors occurred frequently, unable to replicate issue yet
Non-adaptive noise: 976.73 epochs, 1355.1 data loops, 1.87 function evals per line search call, .2397 distance

SVM, avg.dist from true min after 1000 epochs, batchsize=200 [100 samples each]
Adaptive noise: 1000 epochs, 1393 data loops, 1.2934 function evals per line search call, .5000 distance
Improved variance: 1000 epochs, 1327.0 data loops, 1.2695 function evals per line search call, .4951 distance
Exact noise: 1000 epochs, 1322.9 data loops, 1.2291 function evals per line search call, .5087 distance
Non-adaptive noise: 1000 epochs, 1328.1 data loops, 1.2807 function evals per line search call, .5362 distance
